Hello
Hello Friends Health Insurance Good how do I
welcome Mash Bandriya that is of
course welcome to watch this video today
our topic is health insurance is
diabetes
see diabetes is a pathetic household problem
which we call it it is basically of 2 types one is a
person who is normal diabetic that is
taking medicine or tablets second is a
person whose diabetes has reached this condition
this is type-1 where we have to
take insulin the last one we have normal
diabetes in which we are taking medicine or
tablets its pinch is
tasty any question is
told in normal India it is very
unfortunate that by
checking your fasting blood sugar you
can check in a good way whether you have
problem in the morning or not this is
my own experience it is
not a medical test my own experience this is
a completely
unreliable test your fasting sugar is
120 all diarrhea it is forty there are
many different factors of the body on this
we are not like this  You
can check if a person has a sugar problem.
Insurance companies conduct medical checkups
and to check yourself whether you
are diabetic or not, for this there is a
tempered glass measuring cup, it is
called a Chief Vanshi. If we want to
check whether we have a sugar problem
or not, then get this test done.
If its reading is around 5.50, then it
means you are completely healthy. You yourself do
not have any diabetes problem. If it is
around 6, then you have thought that you are going to become a free diabetic
and 606, when a person's
A1C becomes only 5hp, then it means that he has become
diabetic. The
previous level from 6.5 is reduced to 5.5,
mostly because this side is in it, so
you should include this experiment in your diet,
eat multigrain flour, change your presidential
election, follow the number and steps, do
some dance, do aerobics, do
activities and if you
reduce rice and wheat in your diet, then reduce this
level slowly.  It starts decreasing slowly
and you
can easily bring it down to six or seven five percent by making lifestyle changes.
If someone's HbA1c has increased
quickly, the source companies and this medical
science say that
now he
needs medical management and medicines. So
when you are booking a policy in an insurance company, if by
this definition
HbA1c is above five, then you are diabetic.
Because of this, the company may give you a waiver
that now you have become diabetic, so after
three years or two years, like the
terms and conditions of that company,
you will come to the meeting. In this,
apart from the requested, you also have a loading charge on you for having diabetes, that is,
ten-fifteen-twenty percent, the company will
charge you extra money. Now
in India, if someone's SBI lineage crosses 20-7.5, then the
normal insurance company does
not give him a policy. Now,
even if that person buys a policy, if he is touching
1.5 to 1.5  It is coming above this limit,
your company says that now you are
going towards insulin, you basically do
not have to take this medicine, so this becomes a lesson,
if a person is taking medicine for diabetes for more than 89 years, then
insurance companies mostly refuse to give them a policy, saying
that you have become
dependent on one drug and medicine, now if you have been taking this medicine for
years, then they do
not give those policies, so you should keep this thing in
mind, if there is a problem of diabetes then
definitely take your insurance before the onset of diabetes.
Now if a
person had diabetes 5 years ago, 10 years
ago, he took
medicine for four months to a year or two,
after that he got cured, then is his
debit fine as of today's date or not, no,
today's limit is not there, but while
taking the policy, he will have to mention that he has undergone
treatment, now how will the company take it,
that company is Westinghouse, that he is diabetic,
his presentation will be charged with loading, it will
not be charged, it is their internal work, we will
mention this in the proposal form  You do
n't have to pay tax.
Write your medicines in the form with your own hand. Mention when you
started and when you have finished them.
One thing is another. Now, if by
chance
I talk about a female person,
if diabetes goes wrong during pregnancy, that is, if you have
diabetes or hypertension, then it
is compulsory to disclose this while taking the policy.
If you have taken treatment,
you have the option to disclose it. You have to disclose these
small points. Then tomorrow we will talk about it.
I was paying for the last 10 years
and as of today, my company is paying the
daily bills. So,
friends, who told you this? If you are
not an Avengers, then who told you this?
The company does not say that it is our
fault, we will take this penalty or this condition.
Now, one thing can also happen
that after taking the policy, you get diabetes. It will be
covered in this policy.
Till date, this has been the case in some companies.
Most of the companies would have written that
we will not cover diabetes for the first 2 years.
Such strange products have also come in India,
absolutely perfect now.  It is also there, so many times it was
written that within the first 2 years if I have diabetes
and if I put competition in kidney and ghee
then the company will do it, so you should look very carefully, I
told you that after taking the policy I have
diabetes, now the property of this thing is
very high after a minute, because
people have taken it for students, after that
diabetes crossed their body language immediately,
that very quickly most of the people have become
homeless, so now if someone is
ready after taking the policy then it is important to intimate the company that
your chronic has happened in real time, consult
your agent and
tell him properly,
otherwise tomorrow
you will get a huge claim on that time, so now this is the lesson, okay, whether the
person is a type-2 diabetic or not,
he is managing all his fingers,
now one part
goes that till it is made, but if the person will
go on these flames, then in India today there are
three-four such products in which if
a person has insulin, he can also take the policy,
most of the ones which can be
kept on normal flagship stand, if in them  The
insulin in a person's body is
not checked by the policy, so if a person
is already on insulin, then there are some
norms for it, like how old is the Hindi
pitcher and for how many years have you been taking it,
and even after taking it, you are forced to
see the internal of the company, what kind of
job, Chandan Haldi on Bluetooth, they will hang the person
whose kidney is about to get damaged, so
people also get three-four policies
available in India, so
generally speaking,
if you have diabetes, then there is a fine, there is also a
batting print, and
policies are available, but the best
thing is that we should use our lifestyle
and we should improve our
problems like diabetes, period problems in
many ways, that is why a
lot of
people from the IT industry come to us and you will be
very surprised about this thing,
in today's date, at the age of 35 to 40 to 45,
IT improves blood test very quickly
and because of their lifestyle,
working  If there is no work life balance
then it becomes very difficult to manage them
and
if you start having diabetes problem even for a short time in your life then you should never
ignore it,
I request you with folded hands
that if you ever
start taking medicine then follow any
Ayurvedic system, Unani,
Homeopathy, Navratri steps on your own, you do
not have to manage it yourself and especially you just try something from
YouTube,
find out, every person's body type is different,
when every person is born, his
DNA is different and his balance of Vata, Pitta, Kapha,
which is his nature, is different,
so every medicine is
not applicable for every problem, like a general
people are told that they should drink milk,
milk is not beneficial for every problem,
many people say that
take milk at night and put turmeric in it,
turmeric will harm the person whose body is soda,
otherwise it is not like that every medicine is
applicable for everyone, so
whenever there is any type of diabetes
problem  If it starts, then
share a very good guide and your focus should be to
end this debit. The
medicine Zubair that we take in medical science is
a stop element. Take 2 minutes, 4
minutes, 6 minutes at that time and
end it by changing your lifestyle. The
meaning of the disease, whatever you see in allopathy,
one hour before, so that you keep taking the pills,
it is necessary so that they know that
in today's date, to overcome the lifestyle, that is,
they do not have that much will power
or very few people are able to do it,
so this general rule was that keep taking the pills, along with
taking the pills, you should change yourself by taking guidance on
nutrition diet and aerobics in your lifestyle
or
how to manage your oxygen level intake.
Mostly, if people ignore this diabetes, then
in the coming time,
it slowly starts affecting the vital organs of our body, kidney and heart. It has been
mentioned a little in the literature, but take utmost care of yourself,
if any person is suffering from diabetes.  Already,
in the case of diabetes, you
can take action consultancy from us. We
can give you options about
what benefits you get under different policies.
Which are some points? There is
also such a point in which you will get your
policy today and right from the very first day, if you have diabetes, then it does
not die. The
latest information about diabetes will also be
covered from the first day.
But in the cost of the policy, normally I
request people but polish
of available. If any person has to
renew his policy, you
need proper information about your policy, you
need information about portability
or you want to review your policy and return the
policy.
What are the things in health insurance? We are
also going to launch packages in
which we can provide you with product specific information
and
we will start a training mechanism for insurance agents so
that you can know
how to link with ethics and how to develop your business.
For this, you can
contact us after last April. So will
Guide you and not them, this passion
cost, basically I liked it, you took out
time to watch this video,
thank you very much, if you liked this video then
like it, YouTube will promote it a little,
thank you very much Jain